Guide to the William W. Austin papers, 1947-1991.
Austin, William W. papers
- Series II. Journal
  - Journals, February-March 1968 (Box 6, Folder 8)
  - Journals, April-May 1968 (Box 6, Folder 9)
  - Journals, June-August 1968 (Box 6, Folder 10)
  - Journals, September-October 1968 (Box 6, Folder 11)
  - Journals, September-November 1968 (Box 6, Folder 12)
  - Journals, December 1968 (Box 6, Folder 13)
  - Journals, January 1969 (Box 6, Folder 14)
  - Journals, February 1969 (Box 6, Folder 15)
  - Journals, March 1969 (Box 6, Folder 16)
  - Journals, May 1969 (Box 6, Folder 17)
  - Journals, April 1969 (Box 6, Folder 18)
  - Journals, June 1969 (Box 6, Folder 19)
  - Journals, July 1969 (Box 6, Folder 20)
  - Journals, July 24-September 6, 1969 (Box 6, Folder 21)
  - Meetings, September-December 1969 (Box 6, Folder 22)
  - Meetings, January-March 1970 (Box 6, Folder 23)
  - Meetings, April-May 1970 (Box 6, Folder 24)
  - Meetings, June-August 1970 (Box 6, Folder 25)
  - Meetings, September-December 1970 (Box 6, Folder 26)
  - Meetings, January-April 1971 (Box 6, Folder 27)
  - Meetings, May-June 1971 (Box 6, Folder 28)
  - Meetings, July-September 1971 (Box 6, Folder 29)
  - Meetings, October 20-December 31, 1971 (Box 6, Folder 30)
  - Journals, January-March 1972 (Box 6, Folder 31)
  - Journals, April-May 1972 (Box 6, Folder 32)
  - Journals, June-August 1972 (Box 6, Folder 33)
  - Journals, August 27-October 31, 1972 (Box 6, Folder 34)
  - Journals, November-December 1972 (Box 6, Folder 35)
  - Journals, January-March 1973 (Box 6, Folder 36)
  - Journals, April-May 1973 (Box 6, Folder 37)
  - Journals, June-September 1973 (Box 6, Folder 38)
  - Journals, September-December 1973 (Box 6, Folder 39)
  - Journals, January-March 1974 (Box 6, Folder 40)
  - Journals, April-August 1974 (Box 6, Folder 41)
  - Journals, April-August 1974 (Box 6, Folder 41)
  - Journals, August-December 1974 (Box 6, Folder 42)
  - Journals, January-March 1975 (Box 6, Folder 43)
  - Journals, April 1975 (Box 6, Folder 44)
  - Journals, May-June 1975 (Box 6, Folder 45)
  - Journals, July-September 1975 (Box 6, Folder 46)
  - Journals, October-December 1975 (Box 6, Folder 47)
  - Journals, January-March 1976 (Box 6, Folder 48)
  - Journals, April-May 1976 (Box 6, Folder 49)
  - Journals, June-July 1976 (Box 6, Folder 50)
  - Journals, August-October 1976 (Box 6, Folder 51)
  - Journals, November-December 1976 (Box 6, Folder 52)
  - Journals, January-February 1977 (Box 6, Folder 53)
  - Journals, March-May 1977 (Box 6, Folder 54)
  - Journals, June 1-27, 1977 (Box 6, Folder 55)
  - Journals, July-August 1977 (Box 6, Folder 56)
  - Journals, September-October 1977 (Box 6, Folder 57)
  - Journals, November-December 1977 (Box 6, Folder 58)
  - Journals, January-March 1978 (Box 6, Folder 59)
  - Journals, April-May 1978 (Box 6, Folder 62)
  - Journals, June-August 1978 (Box 6, Folder 61)
  - Journals, September-December 1978 (Box 6, Folder 62)
  - Journals, January-April 1979 (Box 6, Folder 63)
  - Journals, May-August 1979 (Box 6, Folder 64)
  - Journals, September 1979 (Box 6, Folder 65)
  - Journals, October-November 1979 (Box 6, Folder 67)
  - Journals, December 1979 (Box 6, Folder 68)
  - Journals, January-March 1980 (Box 6, Folder 69)
  - Journals, April 1980 (Box 6, Folder 70)
  - Journals, May-June 1980 (Box 6, Folder 71)
  - Journals, July-August 1980 (Box 6, Folder 72)
  - Journals, September-October 1980 (Box 6, Folder 73)
  - Journals, November-December 1980 (Box 6, Folder 74)
  - Journals, January-February 1981 (Box 7, Folder 1)
  - Journals, March-April 1981 (Box 7, Folder 2)
  - Journals, May-June 1981 (Box 7, Folder 3)
  - Journals, July 1981 (Box 7, Folder 4)
  - Journals, August-September 1981 (Box 7, Folder 5)
  - Journals, October-November 1981 (Box 7, Folder 6)
  - Journals, December 1981 (Box 7, Folder 7)
  - Journals, January-February 1982 (Box 7, Folder 8)
  - Journals, March-April 1982 (Box 7, Folder 9)
  - Journals, May-August 1982 (Box 7, Folder 10)
  - Journals, May-August 1982 (Box 7, Folder 10)
  - Journals, August-October 1982 (Box 7, Folder 11)
  - Journals, November-December 1982 (Box 7, Folder 12)
  - Journals, January-March 1983 (Box 7, Folder 13)
  - Journals, April-June 1983 (Box 7, Folder 14)
  - Journals, July-September 1983 (Box 7, Folder 15)
  - Journals, October-December 1983 (Box 7, Folder 16)
  - Journals, January-March 1984 (Box 7, Folder 17)
  - Journals, April-May 1984 (Box 7, Folder 18)
  - Journals, June-August 1984 (Box 7, Folder 19)
  - Journals, September-December 1984 (Box 7, Folder 20)
  - Journals, January-March 1985 (Box 7, Folder 21)
  - Journals, April-May 1985 (Box 7, Folder 22)
  - Journals, June-August 1985 (Box 7, Folder 23)
  - Journals, September-December 1985 (Box 7, Folder 24)
  - Journals, January-March 1986 (Box 7, Folder 25)
  - Journals, May 1986 (Box 7, Folder 26)
  - Journals, June-August 1986 (Box 7, Folder 27)
  - Journals, September-December 1986 (Box 7, Folder 28)
  - Journals, January-March 1987 (Box 7, Folder 29)
  - Journals, April-May 1987 (Box 7, Folder 30)
  - Journals, June-August 1987 (Box 7, Folder 31)
  - Journals, September-December 1987 (Box 7, Folder 32)
  - Journals, January-March 1988 (Box 7, Folder 33)
  - Journals, April-June 1988 (Box 7, Folder 34)
  - Journals, July-September 1988 (Box 7, Folder 35)
  - Journals, October-December 1988 (Box 7, Folder 36)
  - Journals, January-March 1989 (Box 7, Folder 37)
  - Journals, April-June 1989 (Box 7, Folder 38)
  - Journals, July-September 1989 (Box 7, Folder 39)
  - Journals, October-December 1989 (Box 7, Folder 40)
  - Journals, January-March 1990 (Box 8, Folder 1)
  - Journals, April-June 1990 (Box 8, Folder 2)
  - Journals, July-August 1990 (Box 8, Folder 3)
  - Journals, September-October 1990 (Box 8, Folder 4)
  - Journals, November-December 1990 (Box 8, Folder 5)
  - Journals, January-February 1991 (Box 8, Folder 6)
  - Journals, March-April 1991 (Box 8, Folder 7)
  - Journals, May-June 1991 (Box 8, Folder 8)
  - Journals, July-August 1991 (Box 8, Folder 9)
  - Journals, September-October 1991 (Box 8, Folder 10)
  - Journals, November-December 1991 (Box 8, Folder 11)
  - Journals, January-February 1992 (Box 8, Folder 12)
  - Journals, March-April 1992 (Box 8, Folder 13)
  - Journals, May-July 1992 (Box 8, Folder 14)
  - Journals, August-October 1992 (Box 8, Folder 15)
  - Journals, November-December 1992 (Box 8, Folder 16)
  - Journals, January-March 1993 (Box 8, Folder 17)
  - Journals, April-May 1993 (Box 8, Folder 18)
  - Journals, June-August 1993 (Box 8, Folder 19)
  - Journals, September-October 1993 (Box 8, Folder 20)
  - Journals, November-December 1993 (Box 8, Folder 21)
- Series III. Articles, Notes, Teaching Materials, and Miscellany
  - Misc. Offprints of Articles by Austin, 1962-1982 (Box 5, Folder 41)
  - "Piston's 4th Symphony" (Article by W. Austin), 1955 (Box 5, Folder 42)
  - Book Reviews by W. Austin (Box 5, Folder 43)
  - "Expressivo" - Article by W. Austin, 1954 (Box 5, Folder 44)
  - "American Oratory 1760-1865," Essay by W. Austin, 1939, 1939 (Box 5, Folder 45)
  - Austin, Entry on Modern Music in MGG (Box 5, Folder 46)
  - Austin's Review of Schuller, Gunther's "Early Jazz" (Box 5, Folder 47)
  - Articles on Berio (Box 5, Folder 48)
  - Waln, "Sisyphi Opus", 1820 (Box 5, Folder 49)
  - Dates and Genealogical Information (RE: Stephen Foster) (Box 5, Folder 50)
  - Misc. Notes on Sessions and Carter (Box 5, Folder 51)
  - Kirkpatrick, Ralph - "The Teaching of Harpsichord Music" (Box 5, Folder 52)
  - Steve Reich Manuscript from Piano Phile, 1967 (Box 5, Folder 53)
  - Austin´s Thesis: "Harmonic Rhyth, in 20th Century Music, 1950 (Box 5, Folder 54)
  - Articles on James Baldwin, 1992-1998 (Box 9, Folder 1)
  - "James Baldwin's Music and James Campbell's 'Music in the Air'" by W. Austin, 1993 (Box 9, Folder 2)
  - "At Harvard, Noel Lee delivers diverse playing", October 12, 1993 (Box 9, Folder 3)
  - Cambridge University Press, 1992-1993 (Box 9, Folder 4)
  - Collier, Eugenia Bibliography and Correspondence, 1992 (Box 9, Folder 5)
  - James Baldwin's "Imagination" from Jimmie's Blues, 1992 (Box 9, Folder 6)
  - Notes on Debussy (Prep. for M2DC), 1996 (Box 9, Folder 7)
  - "Beitrage zur Musikwissenchaft" (for Rhythm Research), 1990 (Box 9, Folder 8)
  - R. Cohen, Charville, 1990 (Box 9, Folder 9)
  - Rousseau/Hunt/Verba, 1967-1989 (Box 9, Folder 10)
  - "New Music", 1967-1988 (Box 9, Folder 11)
  - Austin's Bibliography, 1978-1987 (Box 9, Folder 12)
  - Planning for Music 312, W. Austin, June 1984-January 1985 (Box 9, Folder 13)
  - Papers on Pierre Boulez, 1984 (Box 9, Folder 14)
  - Rhythms Seminar, Music 312, 1984 (Box 9, Folder 15)
  - "Teaching Record-listeners", 1983 (Box 9, Folder 16)
  - Stravinsky's "Fortunate Continuities" and "Legitimate Accidents", 1882-1982 (Box 9, Folder 17)
  - Paper on 19th Century Music, 1981 (Box 9, Folder 18)
  - On Teaching, 1968-1980 (Box 9, Folder 19)
  - "A Chord in Debussy's "Pelleas" and its Reverberations", 1978 (Box 9, Folder 20)
  - Debussy, 1970-1971 (Box 9, Folder 21)
  - Debussy-Paris, October 1962 (Box 9, Folder 22)
  - Conte, 1978-1986 (Box 9, Folder 23)
  - Notes on Faure, Schoenberg, and Strauss, 1981-1983 (Box 9, Folder 24)
  - Schoenberg-Bartok-Stravinsky, 1971-1980 (Box 9, Folder 25)
  - Schoenberg: Music, Notes, Articles (Box 9, Folder 26)
  - "Western Composers and the East: Beethoven to Boulez", 1980 (Box 9, Folder 27)
  - "From Satie to Stockhausen, Muzak, and Environmental Recordings", 1980 (Box 9, Folder 28)
  - "Satie", 1979-1980 (Box 9, Folder 29)
  - "Of the Sorrow Songs: the Cross of Redemption," James Baldwin, July 29, 1979 (Box 9, Folder 30)
  - "Ernst Krenek and Histories" by W. Austin, 1979 (Box 9, Folder 31)
  - Articles on Bob Dylan, 1970-1979 (Box 9, Folder 32)
  - Papers and Writings for Austin's Upcoming Book on Rhythms, 1978 (Box 9, Folder 33)
  - Martini et al., Oxford, 1977 (Box 9, Folder 34)
  - Strawinsky, 1952-1977 (Box 9, Folder 35)
  - Strawinsky, Lausanne, 1952-1975 (Box 9, Folder 36)
  - AHДPEЙ ЗШПAЙ, 1975 (Box 9, Folder 37)
  - V de B. Strawinsky, 1974 (Box 9, Folder 38)
  - Journalistic Writings on IFS, 191947-197175 (Box 9, Folder 39)
  - "The Liberation of Folk Music from National Boundaries", 1971 (Box 9, Folder 40)
  - "Comment écouter la musique," Louis Laloy, Trans. By Austin, 1970 (Box 9, Folder 41)
  - "Mavra", 1970s (Box 9, Folder 42)
  - Essays on Rhythm, 1970s (Box 9, Folder 43)
  - Rhythm Measurements, 1970s (Box 9, Folder 44)
  - Draft: "A History of the Minor Mode", 1969 (Box 9, Folder 45)
  - "The Unity in Strawinsky's WOrks" by Wolf-Eberhard von Lewinski, translated by Austin, 1967 (Box 9, Folder 46)
  - Assorted German Articles on Music, 1966-1967 (Box 9, Folder 47)
  - Charlie Christian, 1966 (Box 9, Folder 48)
  - Press for Austin's "Music in the 20th Century", 1966 (Box 9, Folder 49)
  - Draft: "The Songs of Stephen Foster" by W. Austin, 1957-1964 (Box 9, Folder 50)
  - Notes on Prokofiev, 1963 (Box 9, Folder 51)
  - "Fragment on Music and Language," Adorno, T.W., 1963 (Box 9, Folder 52)
  - Gershwin, 1960 (Box 9, Folder 53)
  - Austin's Notes on Foster (Box 9, Folder 54)
  - MacDowell Artists' Colony, 1957 (Box 9, Folder 55)
  - I.F. Strawinsky, W. Austin Memoranda, 1939-1957 (Box 9, Folder 56)
  - Papers and Correspondence on Schoenberg and his Music, 1950s (Box 9, Folder 57)
  - Memorandi, 1953 (Box 9, Folder 58)
  - "O sacrum convivium motet au Saint-Sacrement," Olivier Messiaen, 1937 (Box 9, Folder 59)
  - "Pièce pour le Tombeau de Paul Dukes," Olivier Messiaen, 1936 (Box 9, Folder 60)
  - Strawinsky Clippings, 1925 (Box 9, Folder 61)
  - Excerpts from Thoreau's Journal, 1840-1857 (Box 9, Folder 62)
  - "Is Sprechstimme a Model for Schoenberg's Instrumental Music?" by Austin (Box 9, Folder 63)
  - Schoenberg Notes (Box 9, Folder 64)
  - Unlabeled Sheet Music (Box 9, Folder 65)
  - Notes on Rottenberg and Hindemith (Box 9, Folder 66)
  - "Strawinksy's Symphony of Psalms" (Box 9, Folder 67)
  - "Words and Music: A Few Notes on Diffraction" by A. Silsbee (Box 9, Folder 68)
  - "Erwartung: A Monodrama in One Act," Words by Marie Pappenheim; Music by Arnold Schoenberg; Translation by Helen Boatwright (Box 9, Folder 69)
  - Philosophical Psych. (Box 9, Folder 70)
  - "Bethlehem," by William Billings (Box 9, Folder 71)
  - Music Bibliography (Box 9, Folder 72)
  - David Smucker's Dissertation: "Philip Paul Bliss and the Origins of the Gospel Music Tradition in the United States, 1850-1876" (Box 9, Folder 73)
  - "Western Composers and the East: Beethoven to Boulez" by William AUustin (Box 9, Folder 74)
  - Papers on Strawinsky (Box 9, Folder 75)
  - Notes on Beethoven (Box 9, Folder 76)
  - Music Theory and Practice ("Eine Theorie des Ubens am Klavier"-Jurgen Uhde) (Box 9, Folder 77)
  - Sartori, Claudio (Box 9, Folder 78)
  - "Music Theory and Practice in a Perspective of a Few Millenia" (Box 9, Folder 79)
  - Vaughan Williams (Box 9, Folder 80)
  - Kandinsky/Schoenberg; Debussy Notes (Box 9, Folder 81)
  - Assorted Handwritten Notes (Box 9, Folder 82)
  - Assorted Music and Lyrics (Box 9, Folder 83)
  - Go Tell (Box 9, Folder 84)
  - "Tell me how long" (Box 9, Folder 85)
  - "Just Above" Notes (Box 9, Folder 86)
  - "Another Country" (Box 9, Folder 87)
  - Music-R's (Box 9, Folder 88)
  - James Baldwin Articles and Notes (Box 9, Folder 89)
  - Music 312, W. Austin (Box 9, Folder 90)
  - Campbell Notes (Box 9, Folder 91)
  - Notes and Drafts on Rhythm, W. Austin (Box 9, Folder 92)
  - "Rhythms," W. Austin (Box 9, Folder 93)
  - Andrei Eshpai (Box 9, Folder 94)
  - Oper in Drama (Box 9, Folder 95)
  - Papers on Olivier Messiaen (Box 9, Folder 96)
  - "American Music" (Box 9, Folder 97)
  - H.E. Krehbiel (Box 9, Folder 98)
  - "The Orientation of Karlheinz Stockhausen," by William W. Austin (Box 9, Folder 99)
  - Histories of American Music (Box 9, Folder 100)
  - Preliminary Thoughts (M2OC) (Box 9, Folder 101)
  - Implicities in M2OC (Box 9, Folder 102)
  - Thoughts on Writing (Box 9, Folder 103)
  - Neue Musik - Prelim. (Box 9, Folder 104)
  - Teaching - Old Ideas (Box 9, Folder 105)
  - Blues and Jazz (Box 9, Folder 106)
  - Eshpai, Krug (Box 9, Folder 107)
  - 218 - Song Texts/Translations (Box 9, Folder 108)
  - "The Rise and Fall of Staff Notation" (Box 9, Folder 109)
  - Popularity (Music) (Box 9, Folder 110)
  - Romantic Intellectualism: Schumann to Schoenberg (Box 9, Folder 111)